UMESH KUMAR SINGH

Noida Sector-53, Uttar Pradesh, 201301

+91- 9708306322 | id.umeshSingh@gmail.com | https://umeshsingh.xyz/

SUMMARY:

Full Stack .NET Developer with 2.5 years of experience in designing, developing, and maintaining web applications using .NET Core, .NET MVC, C#, MS SQL, MySQL, JavaScript, JQuery, and API integrations. Created and lead 10+ websites with .Net Framework. Ability to solve complex problems, optimize backend performance, and contribute to successful project delivery.

EXPERIENCE:

3. CSAT Systems Pvt. Ltd. Noida

Designations: Software Developer Dec 2023 – Present

Technologies: C#, .NET MVC, MS SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax. **Description:** Developed and improved software solutions used by **100+ clients**

2. Freelance + Self-Development & Learning

Remote

Designations: Software Developer July 2023 - Nov 2023

Technologies: C#, .NET Core, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap.

Description: Designed and implemented an inventory management module with features for product tracking.

1. Webkul Software Pvt. Ltd. Noida

Designations: Trainee Software Engineer Jan 2023 - June 2023

Technologies: C#, .NET Core, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap.

Description: Developed and enhanced web applications and reducing API response time by 40%.

SKILLS:

- C#, Java
- Dotnet MVC, ASP .NET Core
- MySQL, MS SQL Server
- ADO.Net, Entity Framework Core, LINQ
- React.js, Angular, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- SMS Integration, Web API / REST API
- Data Structures and Algorithms

LATEST PROJECTS:

- **Web Order-** Developed a complete online ordering system for bars and restaurants, supporting home delivery, takeaway, and Paytm payment integration.
- QR Scan- Built a QR code-based ordering solution allowing customers to scan and view the restaurant menu and place dining orders seamlessly.
- Hand Held- Created a mobile Point-of-Sale (POS) system for bars and restaurants, enabling users to place orders, manage tables/rooms, generate and cancel bills, and print KOTs and invoices.
- **Dashboard-** Designed a dashboard software to manage daily, monthly, and periodic purchase reports, ideal for small and large businesses, hotels, and restaurants.
- **Kitchen Display System (KDS)**:- Developed a real-time Kitchen Display System to streamline order management in the kitchen to reducing manual errors and improving kitchen workflow.

EDUCATION

B.Tech (CSE): Galgotias University, Greater Noida7.54 CGPAAug 2019 – May 2023Intermediate (PCM): HD Jain College, Ara62.40 %Mar 2016 – Mar 2018High School (IT): M.D Carmel School, Jagdishpur10 CGPAMar 2015 – Mar 2016

Cerifications:
ODSA using Java (NPTEL)
OAI-ML (AICTE)
OCyber Security (AICTE)
OCIOUD & Network Security (AICTE)